<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Climate change on AgriSoil</title>
    <link>https://agrisoil.us/tags/climate-change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Climate change on AgriSoil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://agrisoil.us/tags/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Plant Roots in Carbon Sequestration: What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://agrisoil.us/posts/soil-carbon-sequestration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrisoil.us/posts/soil-carbon-sequestration/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Soil carbon sequestration is a process by which carbon dioxide (CO2) is removed from the atmosphere and stored in soils. It is an important part of the global carbon cycle, which helps to regulate climate and contributes to global food security. Soil carbon sequestration is achieved through the growth of plants, which take up atmospheric CO2, release oxygen, and store carbon in their roots and leaves. The carbon is then stored in the soil as organic matter, which can be further stored in the form of humic acids, proteins, and other compounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Management Practices for Soil Conservation: Tips and Techniques</title>
      <link>https://agrisoil.us/posts/soil-erosion-and-conservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrisoil.us/posts/soil-erosion-and-conservation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Soil erosion is a natural process caused by the combined effects of wind, water, climate and human activities, which results in the gradual wearing away of the topsoil. It is a serious environmental concern that can have detrimental impacts on crop production and the quality of the environment. Soil erosion is one of the most important environmental issues of our time and has been linked to problems such as land degradation, loss of vegetation, and pollution of water bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
