<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Carbon sequestration on AgriSoil</title>
    <link>https://www.agrisoil.us/tags/carbon-sequestration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Carbon sequestration on AgriSoil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.agrisoil.us/tags/carbon-sequestration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Bugs and Beasts of the Soil: How They Contribute to a Healthy Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://www.agrisoil.us/posts/soil-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.agrisoil.us/posts/soil-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Soil biodiversity is the variety of living organisms found in the soil and their interactions with each other and their environment. This includes all forms of life, from the smallest microorganisms to invertebrates and vertebrates. Soil supports a wide variety of living organisms and plays a critical role in the health of our planet. It provides essential nutrients, water, and air for plants, animals, and other organisms. It also helps regulate the climate, prevents erosion, and stores carbon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Plant Roots in Carbon Sequestration: What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.agrisoil.us/posts/soil-carbon-sequestration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:04:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.agrisoil.us/posts/soil-carbon-sequestration/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Soil carbon sequestration is a process by which carbon dioxide (CO2) is removed from the atmosphere and stored in soils. It is an important part of the global carbon cycle, which helps to regulate climate and contributes to global food security. Soil carbon sequestration is achieved through the growth of plants, which take up atmospheric CO2, release oxygen, and store carbon in their roots and leaves. The carbon is then stored in the soil as organic matter, which can be further stored in the form of humic acids, proteins, and other compounds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
